# Luca Leone

Email: <u>lucaleone@outlook.com</u>
Tel: <u>+39 3930311662</u>
Linkedin: <u>linkedin.com/in/lucaleone93</u>

GitHub: github.com/lucaleone

# **Summary**

### Software Engineer

I am a passionate software engineer with 4+ years of experience, I love to spread my passion and competence in my work experience. Successful in mobile application, web and video games development with over 500,000 downloads and international prizes. Proficient in discussing and presenting projects to diverse audiences.

## **Skills**

Languages: C#, Java, Python, SQL, PL/SQL, TypeScript

Frameworks: .NET, Angular Database: Oracle SQL

Operating system: Windows, Unix/Linux

Software: Visual Studio, Unity3D, WebStorm, Blender, Git, SVN

# **Work Experience**

# Software Engineer Technical Student CERN

09.2015–10.2016

Geneva, Switzerland

Development of REMUS, SCADA system that provides a 24/7 real-time view of radiation and environment conditions. Large-scale modular platform with redundancy collects data from more than 3000 channels. Software and tools: SQL, PL/SQL, Oracle SQL Developer, Jira, WinCC OA, SVN, Unix/Linux, Windows.

- Developed software 3 new types of Monitoring Station, allowing integration of about 100 new devices
- Realized DB data migration of about 1 billion entries from old DB
- Supervised user testing, installation, and setup of the new monitoring stations
- Implemented new functionalities for the supervision tool
- · Created documentation for users and technician

Student Partner
MICROSOFT

11.2012–06.2014 Rome, Italy

The MSPs is a team chosen to create a reference point for Microsoft technologies in the Universities. Software and tools: C# .NET, Visual Studio, Git, PowerPoint, Photoshop.

- Mentoring, classes to students and professionals in Italian's universities
- Elected Best Student Partner 2013, award given for the contribution to the community
- Achieved 1st price Microsoft Imagine Cup 2013 Windows, 2nd price "mail.ru", Windows Azure cloud grant
- Elected "Tour Owner" for 2 years, participated in about 20 events and hackathons
- Increased students' involvement supervising the publication of more than 40 apps

### **Education**

## **UNIVERSITY ROMA TRE**

09.2012-12.2017

**Bachelor Engineering Computer Science BE** 

Rome, Italy

Study program: Java, C, object-oriented design (OOP), complexity analysis, basic algorithms, design pattern, SQL, OCaml, Unix/Linux, Assembly 8088, Git.

#### **ACADEMY BORN2CODE GROUPAMA**

09.2017-12.2017

Full-time course of Frontend development

Rome, Italy

Study program: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular, TypeScript, Firebase, Progressive Web App PWA.

- Hackathon MAXXI national museum of contemporary art
- Showcase "ilClub", Progressive Web App developed for LUISS ENLABS

# **Projects**

# Game Developer CELIALAB

Students team for video game development focused on arcade games for mobile devices. Software and tools: Unity3D, C#, Visual Studio, Java, Git, Blender, Photoshop, Facebook, Twitter.

- Created 3D models with a focus on rendering performances
- Administered social pages, marketing on Facebook and Twitter
- National finalist in Imagine Cup 2014 games category
- Exclusive participation at XFEST 2014, annual Microsoft event about Xbox game development

# Mobile Developer MOBSOUL

Personal brand for Windows apps, dealt with coding, UI/UX, certification, and marketing. Software and tools: C# .NET, Visual Studio, Photoshop, Facebook, Twitter.

- Published 25 Windows apps, obtained more than 500,000 downloads, released 2 open source libraries
- Achieved access to the beta Windows Store, 7 months before public release
- Selected as young .NET developer for exclusive interview about the experience app development
- Selected 2016 event by "Bending Spoons" for young engineer and entrepreneurs

### **Publications**

#### Microsoft

- "Windows 8 foundations and User interface", 03.2014
- "YouthPanelist e Programming Teacher", 03.2014
- "Windows Phone foundations, async programming", 01.2014
- "Windows 8 foundations", 12.2013
- "Threading and asynchronous programming" at University of Catania, 05.2013
- "App optimization and launch on the Store", 01.2013

#### **GameLab University organization**

- "Introduction to Game Development with Unity3D" at PiCampus Roma, 04.2017
- "Unity3D: game logic and gameplay", 11.2014
- "Unity3D Introduction", 10.2014

#### Startupper

- "Lumis the game" at Microsoft Milan, 05.2014
- "Ulixes project showcase" at Saint Petersburg Russia, 06.2014